

# **ROMAN KHOMETS**

**FRONT-END DEVELOPER (REACT)** 

## PERSONAL SUMMARY

Hi, I'm a quality focused front-end developer with experience in creating web apps using React/Redux/Rest API stack. Pay extreme attention to detail and have a passion for delivering a great user experience. Also, provide strong critical analysis and problem solving. Currently focusing to enhance knowledge of Node.js, Nest and 3D web development

### CONTACTS



Petrikov, Belarus



+375 33 675 53 96









# **SKILLS**

React, Next
Redux (Redux Toolkit)
Typescript
Node, Express, Nest
MongoDB, PostgresQL
Rest API (Axios)
RHF, Formik
Jest
Git
SASS, Responsive Layout
Material UI, Ant Design

## LANGUAGES

Photoshop

English (A2+/B1) Russian/Belarusian (Native)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2021 - current

Freelance

- Created UI for authorization, notifications, product pages
- · Implemented and typed data access layer to server API
- · Created reusable React module components
- Fixed and enhanced existing features according to customer requirements

2019 - 2022

**Individual Entrepreneur (Construction Service)** 

- Developed and implemented strategic business plan in a highly competitive market environment
- Fostering relationships to maintain existing clients, while developing new relationships to attract potential clients
- Designed and implemented marketing campaigns, resulting in ~30% orders increase
- Encourages employees to do their best and increased work productivity immensely

2017 - 2019

**Installation Crew Chief** 

- Managed 3 person team of installers
- Guide efforts to improve technological process in a real and cost effective way, resulting in saving of the worktime for about a half of an hour per day
- Trained new employees

#### **EDUCATION**

2021 - current

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics Engineer of Information Technology and Control

2021 – current IT-Incubator Frontend Developer

2017 – 2021 Bobruisk State College of Forestry Forestry Technician

#### **ACTIVITIES**

DIY amateur
Car travel
The care of homeless animals